<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>SREs on BrainExt</title>
    <link>localhost/sre/</link>
    <description>Recent content in SREs on BrainExt</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="localhost/sre/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>localhost/SRE/SRE_Links/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>localhost/SRE/SRE_Links/</guid>
      <description>Links    SRE Teams     How to get Started / Organize your SRE Team Start and Asses your SRE Journey Building Blocks for SRE Implementing SLOs On-Call SRE Team Lifecycles SRE Reaching Beyond Walls SRE Documentation Organizing an SRE Team SRE Team Lifecycle Amazon Principles 12 -Factor App Overview of SRE Best Practices Google SRE Book Google SRE Workbook Dropbox SRE Career Ladder  Tools     List of Awsome SRE Tools  Random      Cascading Failures(Video)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>localhost/SRE/SRE_WhitePaper/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>localhost/SRE/SRE_WhitePaper/</guid>
      <description>SRE Whitepaper / PPT Outline    Generate SRE WhitePaper / PPT    Generate Docs     Service Overview Charter Playbook Service Documentation Best Practices Doc Postmortem Framework Production Readiness Review  Document Repository     Where would they go? DevOps would be good (wiki and repo) but not in prod A share would be good, but there is not an easy way to search A wiki would be good, but there is not a good way to store long scripts (would have to link) Should be able to replicate to other environments for ease of access  Key Tenants     Blameless Postmortems Management Buy-In Eliminate Toil Defined SLOs Defined Monitoring and Metrics &amp;lsquo;Operational Excellence&amp;rsquo; Public facing metrics (status Dashboard)  Team Organization     1 Week On-Call Kitchen Sink Type Org  TimeLine     Create plan pending mgmt buy in  Devils Advocate     What is Bad / What could go wrong?</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
